

INFO



Name Nauman Khan



Address

Riyadh Saudi Arabia Al Nadhwa



Phone +966583102380



Email nomanysfzai@gmail.com



PMI-RMP® number 36112

CSWIP 3.1 ASNT-RT,PAUT,UT,MT,PT level II

Language

English: Fluent Urdu: Fluent

Nationality

Pakistani

SOCIAL

in

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ in/nauman-khan-800644a2



Facebook

https://www.facebook

REFERENCES

Project Engineer-Jacobs/Worley
Cell: +966531580013
hany.barakat@jacobszate.com

Aftab Azeem
Element Material Tech
Cell:+966554452686
aftab.azeem@element.com

Nauman Khan

QaQc Mechanical/Welding & NDT Inspection



WORK EXPERIENCE (Summary)

2020-PRES QaQc Mechanical/Welding and NDT JACOBS ZATE/WORLEY SWCC Project KSA

The 412km long twin pipeline, with two 88" pipes will be one of the largest water transmission system worldwide and will transport 1.2 million m^3 of portable water per day. The project cost is (\$5.64\$ billion)

2018-2020 **Third Party Inspector Location: KSA**ELEMENT MATERIAL TECHNOLOGY

Ensured successful completion of Mechanical Welding & NDT Inspections deliverables and monitoring of project performance for Inspection tasks, schedules and costs

Follow-up tasks with field team, deadlines and milestones for all stake holders and resources.

2017-2018 *Mech. Welding & NDT Supervisor KSEW Location: Pakistan*

➤ Inspect fabrication, welding, DT & NDT until commissioning of SLTS.

SLTS. 2014-2016 **QaQc Inspection Engineer**

Descon Engg. Location: Pakistan

Supervising Pre-commissioning & commissioning activities.

2014-2014 **Qc Shutdown Supervisor Location: Qatar**DESCON ENGINEERING QATAR

> Supervises all direct team shutdown piping and equipment's

works. 2011-2013 NDT INSPECTOR Location: Pakistan INSPECTESTS PVT LTD.

➤ Supervise all NDT(VT,RT,UT,MT,PT,PAUT) Inspection activities.

2010-2011 Foundry/Machine Shop QaQc Supervisor ATLAS ENGINEERING Location: Pakistan

> Supervises all team Foundry and Machining activities.



EDUCATION

2012-2016 Dadabhouy Institute of Higher Education, Karachi Pakistan

Bachelor of Technology (Hons) in Metallurgy & Material Engineering from Dadabhouy Institute of Higher Education.



SKILLS AND EXPERTIZE

Mechanical Fab	
Welding & NDT	
Risk Management	
Project Mgt	
Quality Control	

QaQc Mechanical /Welding & NDT Inspection



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have more than 13-years experience of Mechanical & Welding Inspection with reputable Clients including Dolphin Energy, Qatar Petroleum, Aramco, SWCC & Shipyard. Where I got professional experience. I have Bachelor degree in Metallurgy and Material Science & RMP-PMI.

Specifically in Welding technology I have Cswip 3.1. as well as NDT (RT, UT, PAUT,PT, MT) level II. I have also experience as a Third Party Welding Inspector in which all the Welding Technique is used with different clients including Manual, Automatic or Semi-Automatic welding machines. After completion of Welding NDT (VT, RT, UT, PT, MT) is witnessed by me then Destructive testing (Tensile Test, Bend Test, Hardness Test, Chemical and Failure) is also include in our scope in Element Material Technology KSA.

I have also experience as a consultant in Worley SWCC project where we review all procedures for Welding, NDT & DT, Hydro test till the dossier and commissioning. I have excellent communication skills with ability to relay the results of the inspection and to keep excellent records of all NDT & DT tests runs and inspection conducted. I pay close attention to detail and I have the knowledge and experience to ensure that all work meets the specification, quality and safety standards set forth by the company and the local, state and federal regulations. I have the physical strength and stamina to perform any job.



TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Supervise, co-ordinate and schedule the activities of workers who shape, form and join metal parts or products to specified dimensions, machine metal into parts, products, tools and dies in Machine Shop. Establish methods to meet work schedules and co-ordinate work activities with other departments Requisition materials and supplies

Resolve work problems and recommend work measures to improve productivity

ENGINEERING EXPERTISE:-

- Witnessing PQR and WQT & HSS Qualification Test.
- Preparing NDT and DT Scope according To ASME Sec IX, API 1104, AWS D1.1 and Aramco Standard.
- Monitoring Stage Inspection from Base Material, Welding Consumables, NDT & DT till Final Stage.
- Prepare Final PQR and Welder Qualification Cards

CONSTRUCTION EXPERTISE:-

- Checking of Material, MRIR & MTC and Preparation of Reports.
- Practical experience of performing VT, RT, DPT, MPI,WFMT
- Inspection of Fit-up, Welding of joint & Tie in Joints as per Drawing and Project Specification.
- Inspection of Vessels, Heat Exchangers, Storage Tanks, AFC, Filters, Furnace, Column and Boilers before and after Mechanical Cleaning & Repairing & keep Record of the Observation and Test Reports as per API 510 and API 653. Inspection of Painting of Steel Structure, Piping, Vessels, Storage Tanks after Normal Scraping & Grit/Sand Blasting as per Project Specification & keep Record of the Test Report.
- Responsible for the NDT of Welding Joint (VT, RT, DPT, MPI, WFMT) as per ASME Section IX & keep Record of the Test Report.
- Responsible for WQT as per WQT Specification.
- Responsible for Fabrication & Installation of Steel Pipes as per Drawing.
- Arranging NDT (DPT, MT, UT, RT, RBI and WFMT) as per ASME code section V.
- Inspection of Mechanical Valves before and after Pressure Test.
- Inspection of Bolted Joints after Changing of new Gaskets & Bolt Tightening.

QAQC Mechanical/Welding & NDT Inspection



TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Feb 2020-Present JACOBS | Worley SWCC Project KSA
- Performs quality control requirements to be performed for company engineering projects: issues general manual for quality control supported by project specific requirements in order to achieve the proper level of quality and fitness for purpose of company installations.
- Provides problem solving services to different company teams in matters that fall within the scope of the team function and responsibilities, by analyzing the problem, performing appropriate laboratory testing, non- destructive examination, chemical analysis, etc.
- using the team laboratory or other local or external facilities and provide technical reports and studies in order to avoid reoccurrence. Prepares and provides technical and contractual requirements for different inspection/corrosion agreements and consultancy services to be contracted locally and abroad. This is achieved through communications with various company teams, local and overseas organizations and department heads in order to obtain the most viable and cost effective agreement. Shares in performing technical and quality audits on vendors, manufacturers, bidders, contractors, etc. by visiting and evaluating their capabilities, experience resources, quality systems, etc. in order to assess their suitability for inclusion into the team and/or company contracts or service agreements.
- Controls and supervises the inspection activities related to in-service plant and equipment, e.g. gathering centers, booster stations, tank farms, pipelines, etc.
- The activity is achieved by planning and supervising the inspection/corrosion work to be made by subordinates and issuing repair, protection, examination and retesting requirements then issuing validity certificates and future recommendations.
- The purpose of the work is to ensure the safety and integrity of plant and equipment in order to prevent/minimize hazards to life and property, and ensure continuity of operations.



QAQC Mechanical/Welding & NDT Third Party Inspector

- 15 Oct 2018-31 Jan 2020 Element Material Technology Location: KSA
- Third party Inspection of Material and Preparation of Reports.
- Practical experience of performing VT, RT, DPT, MPI,WFMT
- Inspection of Fit-up, Welding & PQR as per Project Specification.
- Inspection of Vessels, Heat Exchangers, Storage Tanks, AFC, Filters, Furnace, Column and Boilers before
 and after Mechanical Cleaning & Repairing & keep Record of the Observation and Test Reports as per API
 510 and API 653.
- Inspection of Painting of Steel Structure, Piping, Vessels, Storage Tanks after Normal Scraping & Grit/Sand Blasting as per Project Specification & keep Record of the Test Report.
- Responsible for the NDT of Welding Joint (VT, RT, DPT, MPI, WFMT) as per ASME Section IX & keep Record
 of the Test Report.
- Responsible for WQT as per WQT Specification.
- Responsible for Welder cards & reports preparation.

QAQC Mechanical/Welding & NDT Inspection



Shipbuilding/Ship manufacturing QC/NDE Supervisor

22 May 2017-10 Oct 2018

KSEW

Location: Pakistan

- Lead & manage multiple quality control teams in accordance to Inspection Testing Procedure (ITP),
 Quality plan (QP), NDT Procedure/Plan & Welding Procedure Qualification (WPS)
- Engage in Coordination with different 3rd party classification societies such as Lloyd Register & Bureau Veritas to witness WPQR, WQT & Inspection Reports.
- Quality Control project supervision about inspection of fabrication, welding & NDT work. To Check & Review all Inspection Reports such as NDT (RT, UT, MPI, DPT), Fabrication, welding, dimension & casting reports and forward to 3rd party classification societies or client for the acceptance.
- Responsible to conduct Welding Procedure Qualification Record WPQR & Welders Qualification Tests WQT for upcoming projects in front of 3rd party classification societies.
- Final inspection as per quality standards & procedures before handing over to Client. Evaluate the qualifications of Welders & QC personnel such as Welding Inspectors & NDT technicians.
- Supports and participate to all internal/external audits.
- Ensure that all weld, welder and welding activities are correctly specified and carried out in accordance with the relevant international codes, client specifications and applicable company welding procedures.
- QMS / QHSE Implementation, management reporting and coordination.
 Implementation of ISO 9001, 18001, 14001 and ISO 17025 for calibration lab.
- Manage and supervise the operational activities and solving technical issues.
 Read and understand specifications, reference code and standard.
- Review and interpret contract drawings.



QAQC Engineer

1 May 2014- 31 Dec 2016

Descon Engineering Ltd.

- Location: Pakistan
- I have Onshore Pipeline Projects, Plant Piping, Pressure Vessels and structural fabrication.
- Extensive experience in conducting procedure qualification and welder performance qualification tests and interpreting Radiography films.
- I have Expertise in development of Inspection & Test Plan, project specific procedures and method statement for Fabrication/Welding/NDT procedures based on project requirements and as per international codes & standards.
- I have experience in reviewing the operational practices, identifying the areas of obstruction / quality
 failures, and advising on system and process changes for qualitative improvement. Proactively
 coordinating with the QA / QC personnel at various Maintenance and construction sites for
 implementation of the current / revised standards,
- I have experience in testing procedures and specifications. Acquainted with working knowledge of various International Codes and Standards such as AWS, EN, API, ASME, ASTM, ANSI, and ISO Standards.
- I have experience in applying knowledge of welding principles, metallurgical properties, base and welding materials to ensure conformance to the specifications and that all welding filler metals used are as specified for material.
- Distinction Quality Reports and Variance Statements for apprising management of shutdowns/turnarounds and project progress as per Quality Parameters.
- carrying out routine & periodical inspection of various activities for construction projects and notifying the non-conformances identified during inspection.

QAQC Mechanical/Welding & NDT Inspection



Qatar Shutdown Inspection Supervisor

- 04 Jan 2014-24 Mar 2014

Descon Engineering

- **Location: Qatar**
- Responsible for the overall Quality control of all the construction activities on projects.
- Responsible for all inspections at site inclusive Witnessing, Recording, Reporting the results and Resolving any problem arising.
- Carried out visual inspection, welding consumable verification, dimensional check,
- Performance test, welder qualification, welder training and performance monitoring.
- Approve welding procedure specification (WPS/PQR), Witness and approve welder.
- Welding operator performance qualification (WPQ).
- Bend tests, Impact & Hardness Tests.
- Review Test Certificates with respect to standards / specifications.



NDE Inspector

- 01 Dec 2011- 01 July 2013 Inspectests Pvt Ltd.
- Location: Pakistan
- Arranging NDT (DPT, MT, UT, PAUT, RT, RBI and WFMT) as per ASME code section V.
- Responsible for the NDT of Welding Joint (VT, DPT, MPI, WFMT) as per ASME Section IX & keep Record of the Test Report.
- Inspection of Pre-Heat/PWHT as per ASME VIII Division 1 and keep record of Test Reports.
- Practical experience of performing VT, DPT, MPI,WFMT
- Inspection of Pre-Heat/PWHT as per ASME VIII Division 1 and keep record of Test Reports.
- Inspection of Soap Film Test (SFT) of Exchanger, and Furnace Tubes.
- Inspection of Piping Fabrication as per Project Specification, Codes and Standards.
- NDE Services Radiographic Testing (RT) & Ultrasonic Testing (UT)
- Magnetic Particle Testing (MPT) & Dye Penetrant Testing (DPT)



QAQC Foundry & Machine Shop Supervisor



10 Sep 2010- 30 Sep 2011

Atlas Engineering

- **Location: Pakistan**
- In Atlas Engineering we prepare Honda Atlas & Suzuki Automobile parts.
- I perform all stage inspection of Core Making.
- Inspection of Foundry Furnace.
- After shaping of material, the machining of cape & core.
- Responsible to control rejection during Foundry processes.
- QaQc Inspection in Fettling Shop.
- Stage by stage Machine Shop Inspection.
- Responsible for all casting, melting and final product according to international standard.



Multiple Sector Shutdowns Experiences

- Dolphin Energy Plant Shutdown Qatar
- Engro Fertilizer Plant Shutdown
- Fatima Fertilizer Plant Shutdown
- SNGPL Gas Plant Pakistan Shutdown
- PTA LOTTE Chemical Plant Shutdown
- FFBL Fertilizer Plant Shutdown